SOFIA ALTURAS Architect and Urbanist

Mobile: +1 (912) 308-8585 • Email: sofiaalturasarquitetura@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://sofiaalturasarq.wixsite.com/saarchitecture

SUMMARY

I am a young Portuguese architect, who recently graduated from SCAD, with a master's in Design for Sustainability.

Exposed to different cultures and with expanded horizons, I am a very organized and friendly architect with 5+ years of successful experience working in Architectural offices and clients.

SKILLS

AutoCAD Adobe Creative Suit
Sketchup 3D Rendering (Lumion)

BIM (Revit and Archicad) Microsoft Office

WORK EXPERIENCE

SA Arquitetura • Architecture Atelier

2020 - Present

Self-owned ongoing projects in Brazil and Portugal:

- Responsible for all project phases assignments including programming client needs, conceptual design, schematic design, design development, space planning, and construction documentation
- Selecting furniture and styles for the projects
- · Coordinate construction site, making sure everything goes accordingly to the project
- · Clients satisfied with finals results

SCAD Museum of Art • Museum

September, 2021 - May, 2022

- · Helped visitors through the museum and made them feel comfortable and welcome
- · Connecting to other employees, staff, and visitors using international background and experiences
- Gave tours to different-sized groups in different languages while being adaptable to each group to foster a good learning environment

MAAI Arquitetura Integrada • Architecture Atelier

February, 2019 - August, 2020

- Internship:
- Worked under other architect's supervision
- Responsible for different tasks in multiple projects, from taking measures on the project site to design development and construction documents
- Interns changed teams every three months, given the opportunity to work with different architects and projects types
- Junior Architect:
- In charge of a house renovation
- · The bridge between the clients and the office using my communitive skills and being well-liked by people
- In charge of all the project phases
- Worked under the supervision of the architect chief of the office

Morada 3112 • Architecture Atelier

August, 2018 - January, 2019

- Worked in a smaller office, directly under the architect owner
- · Opportunity to participate in meetings and see up close the progress of a project
- Worked on both commercial and residential projects

Alf Arquitetura • Architecture Atelier

January, 2018 - August, 2018

- Worked in commercial and residential projects
- Opportunity to learn AutoCAD and SketchUp by using them every day
- · Learned to work in an office environment

MAIS Arquitetura • Architecture Atelier

April, 2017 - October, 2017

- First experience as an intern
- Worked with two architects and help them with everything they needed

MAAI Arquitetura Integrada • Isabel Veiga

April, 2017 - October, 2017

- First contact with a working architect
- · Opportunity to shadow a renowned architect during meetings with clients and project development
- Got to visit stores and learn about materials and finishes
- A great advantage to see the life of a working architect before starting to work

EDUCATION

2022	Savannah	College of	Art and	Design -	- SCAD
------	----------	------------	---------	----------	--------

M.A in Design for Sustainability

2020 Universidade de Brasília (Brazil)

Bachelor Degree in Architecture and Urbanism

2014 School Of The Nations (Brazil)

High School